In this lecture, we're going to learn about an AWS AI service in the area of natural language
processing called as Amazon Translate. So Amazon Translate is an AWS language translation
service, which allows language translation across 75 different languages. And you can see
on the homepage of Amazon Translate, these are the 75 different languages. It supports from
the translation perspective. So now let's see how this works. It allows language translation in
real time. Let's say you have text in English or it also allows batch translation where you
can upload the document in an S3 bucket. And then it runs through Amazon Translate. And it does
the translation in the language that you have selected. So what are the various capabilities of
Amazon Translate? So it allows you to do the document translation. Now let's say you are selling
a product to the global audience and you are receiving feedback comments or orders in a language
that you might not be able to detect as a source language. So it allows automatic source language
detection. Then it can also do profanity masking. And then as we discussed, it allows real time and
batch processing. So what are the use cases for Amazon Translate? So first one is Translate user
generated content from RSS feed, social media and so on. So if you use Instagram and you identified
preferred language as English and let's say somebody posts a comment on your post in German.
Then you will see a small caption there which allows you to translate that comment from German
to your preferred language. Then it can also do real time translation of chat, email,
help with this. Now let's say you have an English speaking agent. And on the other side,
the customer is typing content Spanish, then the agent can use Amazon Translate to understand
the customer query and then respond back. And then finally, it also allows you to do
sentiment analysis towards your product and determine whether the overall feedback on the product
is neutral, positive or negative. Now let's go to the console and take a quick look.